{
  "chapter_metadata": {
    "chapter_id": "10.English.01",
    "standard": "10",
    "subject": "History",
    "medium": "English",
    "chapter_name": "Historiography : Development in the West"
  },
  "questions": [
    {
      "question_id": 1,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Who is considered the founder of modern historiography?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "René Descartes", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Leopold von Ranké", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Voltaire"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 2,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which Greek historian first used the term 'History' for his book?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Herodotus", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Hegel", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Foucault", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "René Descartes", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Herodotus"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 3,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The method of analysis based on opposites is known as _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Synthesis", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Dialectics", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Numismatics", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Epigraphy", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Dialectics"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 4,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Who wrote the book entitled 'Archaeology of Knowledge'?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Michel Foucault", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Simone de Beauvoir", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Michel Foucault"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 5,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "In which year was Gottingen University founded in Germany?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "1737 C.E.", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "1789 C.E.", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "1831 C.E.", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "1926 C.E.", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "1737 C.E."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 6,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "What is the study of inscriptions called?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Numismatics", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Epigraphy", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Genealogy", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Linguistics", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Epigraphy"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 7,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The world-famous treatise 'Das Kapital' was written by _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Friedrich Hegel", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Leopold von Ranké", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Michel Foucault", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Karl Marx"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 8,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The earliest inscription (4500 B.C.E.) is currently displayed at _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Berlin University", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Louvre Museum", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "British Museum", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Mesopotamia", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Louvre Museum"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 9,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which scholar insisted on verifying the reliability of historical documents?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "René Descartes", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Herodotus", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "René Descartes"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 10,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The Annales School of historiography was started by ______ historians.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "German", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "French", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Greek", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "British", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "French"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 11,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "What is the study of coins called?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Epigraphy", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Linguistics", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Numismatics", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Genealogy", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Numismatics"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 12,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "History is originally a _______ term.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Latin", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Greek", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "German", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "French", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Greek"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 13,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "According to Hegel, the contrary theory to a thesis is called _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Synthesis", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Antithesis", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Hypothesis", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Dialectics", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Antithesis"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 14,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Leopold von Ranké was associated with the _______ University.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Gottingen", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Berlin", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Paris", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Oxford", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Berlin"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 15,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Who wrote the book 'Reason in History'?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Friedrich Hegel", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "René Descartes", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Friedrich Hegel"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 16,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Feminist historiography was established through the writings of _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Michel Foucault", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Simone de Beauvoir", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Leopold von Ranké", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Simone de Beauvoir"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 17,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The study of lineage is known as _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Genealogy", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Numismatics", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Epigraphy", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Linguistics", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Genealogy"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 18,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "In modern historiography, questions are _________, meaning they are about human deeds.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Theocentric", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Anthropocentric", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Scientific", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Philosophical", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Anthropocentric"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 19,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Who stated that 'history is the history of class struggle'?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Hegel", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Ranké", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Descartes", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Karl Marx"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 20,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The book 'Discourse on the Method' was written by _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "René Descartes", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Hegel", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Foucault", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "René Descartes"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 21,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The tradition of historiography can be traced back to the ______ civilization.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Greek", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Sumer", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Roman", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Indian", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Sumer"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 22,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which scholar believed archaeology explains transitions rather than ultimate truth?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Leopold von Ranké", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Michel Foucault", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Hegel", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Michel Foucault"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 23,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The method used in physical and natural sciences to verify knowledge is ______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "The Dialectic method", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "The Empirical method", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Historical research", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Epigraphy", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "The Empirical method"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 24,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Voltaire's original name was _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "René Descartes", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "François-Marie Arouet", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Michel Foucault", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Lucien Febvre", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "François-Marie Arouet"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 25,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which of these is NOT a discipline useful in historical research?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Manuscriptology", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Numismatics", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Laboratory observation of historical events", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Archival Science", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Laboratory observation of historical events"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 26,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "What is the study of language called?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Linguistics", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Genealogy", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Numismatics", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Epigraphy", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Linguistics"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 27,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Who wrote 'The Theory and Practice of History'?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Hegel", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Leopold von Ranké", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Leopold von Ranké"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 28,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "According to Marx, human history is the history of ______ struggle.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Racial", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Class", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Religious", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Geographical", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Class"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 29,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Synthesis is the process of arriving at a _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "New Thesis", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Contradiction", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Falsehood", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Scientific law", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "New Thesis"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 30,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The Louvre museum is located in _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Germany", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "France", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "England", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Greece", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "France"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 31,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which school emphasized studying climate, agriculture, and local people?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Marxist School", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Annales School", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Berlin School", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Scientific School", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Annales School"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 32,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "A scholar who writes a critical historical narrative is called a _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Scientist", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Historian", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Philosopher", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Linguist", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Historian"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 33,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Till the 18th century, European universities were only interested in ______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Modern Science", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Divine phenomena", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Class struggle", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Archeology", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Divine phenomena"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 34,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The term 'Dialectics' was used by ______ to understand opposites.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "G.W.F. Hegel", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Michel Foucault", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "René Descartes", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "G.W.F. Hegel"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 35,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "What is the study of old manuscripts called?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Archival Science", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Manuscriptology", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Numismatics", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Epigraphy", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Manuscriptology"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 36,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Foucault's method is specifically called the _______ of Knowledge.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Genealogy", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Archaeology", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Philosophy", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "History", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Archaeology"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 37,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Who criticized imaginative narration of history?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Leopold von Ranké", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Hegel", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Leopold von Ranké"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 38,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "History presents a graph of mankind's journey through past human ______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Thoughts", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Deeds", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Dreams", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Inventions", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Deeds"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 39,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which scholar argued that Arrange events chronologically is not right?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Hegel", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Michel Foucault", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Karl Marx", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Michel Foucault"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 40,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "The fragment of the earliest Sumerian inscription dates back to ______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "1737 C.E.", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "4500 B.C.E.", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "1596 C.E.", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "1818 C.E.", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "4500 B.C.E."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 41,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Analysis of lettering style is a discipline used in ______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Natural Science", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Historical research", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Laboratory experiment", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Physical science", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Historical research"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 42,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which book is well known for Leopold von Ranké?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "The Secret of World History", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Das Kapital", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Reason in History", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "The Histories", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "The Secret of World History"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 43,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "In history, it is not possible to formulate ______ that remain true regardless of time and space.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Questions", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Laws", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Stories", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Inscriptions", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Laws"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 44,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Herodotus belongs to the _______ century B.C.E.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Fourth", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Fifth", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Eighteenth", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Nineteenth", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Fifth"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 45,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "What is the science of managing archives called?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Archival Science", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Archeology", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Epigraphy", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Manuscriptology", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Archival Science"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 46,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "According to Hegel, True-False and Good-Bad are direct ______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Synonyms", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Opposites", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Theses", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Syntheses", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Opposites"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 47,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Feminist historiography focuses on rethinking the ______ dominated perspective.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Female", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Male", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Scientific", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Ancient", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Male"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 48,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which scholar wrote about prison administration from a historical perspective?",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Voltaire", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Michel Foucault", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Hegel", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Ranké", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Michel Foucault"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 49,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "A historian needs an expert who knows the _______ to read a historical document.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Future", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Language and script", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Laboratory method", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Scientific laws", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Language and script"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 50,
      "question_type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Modern historiography with its characteristics has its roots in _______.",
      "options": [
        { "option_id": 1, "text": "Ancient Roman writings", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 2, "text": "Ancient Greek historical writings", "is_correct": true },
        { "option_id": 3, "text": "Ancient Indian Vedas", "is_correct": false },
        { "option_id": 4, "text": "Ancient Egyptian hieroglyphs", "is_correct": false }
      ],
      "answer": "Ancient Greek historical writings"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 51,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is Historiography?",
      "answer": "The writing of critical historical narrative is known as 'Historiography'. A scholar who writes such a narrative is called a historian."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 52,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Who is a Historian?",
      "answer": "A historian is a scholar who writes a critical historical narrative based on relevant historical references and conceptual frameworks."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 53,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Why is the empirical method not possible in historical research?",
      "answer": "It is not possible because we were not present in historical time and space, and historical events cannot be recreated for experiments."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 54,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What are the four main characteristics of modern historiography?",
      "answer": "It is based on scientific principles, its questions are anthropocentric, answers are supported by reliable evidence, and it presents mankind's journey."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 55,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What does 'Anthropocentric questions' mean in history?",
      "answer": "It means questions are about the deeds of members of ancient human societies of a particular period, without suggesting interrelations with the Divine."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 56,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Who was Herodotus?",
      "answer": "Herodotus was a Greek historian of the fifth century B.C.E. who first used the term 'History' for his book entitled 'The Histories'."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 57,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was René Descartes' insistence regarding historical research?",
      "answer": "He insisted on verifying the reliability of historical documents by critically examining them and never accepting anything as true until doubt is excluded."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 58,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Why is Voltaire called the founder of modern historiography?",
      "answer": "Because he opined that understanding social traditions, trade, economy, and agriculture was as important as objective truth and chronology in history writing."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 59,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the 'Dialectics' method proposed by Hegel?",
      "answer": "It is a method of analysis based on opposites (like True-False) where a thesis is followed by an antithesis to arrive at a synthesis."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 60,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Define 'Thesis' and 'Antithesis' in the context of Dialectics.",
      "answer": "A thesis is a theory proposed at the beginning, while an antithesis is another theory proposed which is contrary to the thesis."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 61,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is 'Synthesis'?",
      "answer": "Synthesis is the process of proposing a new thesis that includes the gist of both the initial thesis and the contrary antithesis after logical discussion."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 62,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Which scholar wrote the book 'Reason in History'?",
      "answer": "Georg Wilhelm Friedrich Hegel, a German philosopher, wrote the well-known book 'Reason in History' to present historical reality logically."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 63,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did Leopold von Ranké emphasize in his critical method?",
      "answer": "He emphasized the utmost importance of information gathered through original documents and insisted that all associated documents be examined with greatest care."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 64,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Name the books written by Leopold von Ranké.",
      "answer": "His articles are published in two books: 'The Theory and Practice of History' and 'The Secret of World History'."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 65,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was Karl Marx's view on history?",
      "answer": "Marx argued that history was not about abstract ideas but about living people, where human relationships are shaped by fundamental needs and means of production."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 66,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "According to Karl Marx, what causes class struggle?",
      "answer": "Inequality in the accessibility of means of production to different strata of society causes a division into classes, leading to exploitation and struggle."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 67,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the Annales School?",
      "answer": "It is a school of historiography started by French historians in the 20th century that shifted focus to climate, local people, agriculture, and trade."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 68,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is Feminist Historiography?",
      "answer": "It is the restructuring of history from the perspective of women, emphasizing their inclusion and rethinking male-dominated historical perspectives."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 69,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Who was Simone de Beauvoir?",
      "answer": "She was a French writer who helped establish the fundamentals of feminism, driving historical research to focus on various aspects of women's lives."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 70,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did Michel Foucault argue in 'Archaeology of Knowledge'?",
      "answer": "He argued that arranging historical events in chronological order is wrong and that archaeology attempts to explain transitions in the past."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 71,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the 'Archaeology of Knowledge' as a method?",
      "answer": "It is Foucault's method of historical analysis that focuses on explaining transitions in history and subjects unacknowledged areas like medicine to analysis."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 72,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is Numismatics?",
      "answer": "Numismatics is a discipline used in historical research that involves the study of coins to understand the past."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 73,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Define Epigraphy.",
      "answer": "Epigraphy is the specialized branch of historical study that focuses on the study of inscriptions found on ancient artifacts or monuments."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 74,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is Genealogy?",
      "answer": "Genealogy is a discipline used in historical research that specifically studies lineage and family history through various records."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 75,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How did ancient people pass on stories of ancestors?",
      "answer": "They used means like cave paintings, story-telling, singing songs, and ballads to pass on stories of life and valour to the next generation."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 76,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Where can we find the earliest Sumerian inscription?",
      "answer": "The earliest inscription, dating back to 4500 B.C.E. and recording a battle between kingdoms, is displayed at the Louvre museum in France."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 77,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was the significance of Gottingen University founded in 1737?",
      "answer": "It was the first university to have an independent department of history, leading to other German universities becoming centres of historical studies."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 78,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How can experts examine the authenticity of a historical document?",
      "answer": "They use criteria such as lettering style, author's writing style, manufacturing date, type of paper, and stamps of authority to check authenticity."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 79,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What are the roots of modern historiography?",
      "answer": "Modern historiography, based on scientific principles and anthropocentric questions, has its roots in ancient Greek historical writings."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 80,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What themes did the Annales school focus on?",
      "answer": "It focused on climate, local people, agriculture, trade, technology, means of communication, social divisions, and collective psychology."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 81,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What subjects became part of historical writing after the expansion of its scope?",
      "answer": "Subjects like literature, architecture, sculpture, music, dance, drama, films, and television became part of historical writing practice."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 82,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Who wrote 'Discourse on the Method'?",
      "answer": "René Descartes wrote 'Discourse on the Method', where he gave rules for the scientific method of research, like excluding grounds of doubt."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 83,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is 'Synthesis' in Hegel's philosophy?",
      "answer": "Synthesis is the final stage of dialectics where a new theory is proposed that includes the gist of both the thesis and the antithesis."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 84,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Why is history not possible to formulate universal laws?",
      "answer": "Because historical events are unique, tied to specific time and space, and cannot be proven repeatedly through laboratory experiments."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 65,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the primary objective of historical research?",
      "answer": "The objective is to understand the chronology of past events and their interconnections through critical examination of sources."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 86,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How does a historian select events for their narrative?",
      "answer": "A historian selects events based on the conceptual framework they adopt and the specific story they intend to tell to the readers."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 87,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the role of an expert in reading historical documents?",
      "answer": "An expert is needed to know the language and script of the document to read it and understand its meaning accurately."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 88,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What does the Sumerian inscription in the Louvre show?",
      "answer": "It shows a fragment with a forward-marching file of soldiers holding shields and spears, with the General in the front."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 89,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was the view of European universities prior to the 18th century?",
      "answer": "They were interested only in philosophical discourses revolving around Divine phenomena and the relationship between God and the world."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 90,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Which book is known as a world-referred treatise by Karl Marx?",
      "answer": "'Das Kapital' is the world-referred treatise written by Karl Marx that explains his theories on class and economy."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 91,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the study of inscriptions called?",
      "answer": "The study of inscriptions is called Epigraphy, which is a key discipline for reconstructing ancient history from physical records."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 92,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How did Foucault describe the goal of archaeology?",
      "answer": "Foucault described that archaeology does not strive to reach ultimate historical truth but attempts to explain various transitions in the past."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 93,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did Voltaire believe was equally important in historiography?",
      "answer": "He believed social traditions, trade, economy, and agriculture were equally important along with objective truth and chronology."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 94,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is 'Manuscriptology'?",
      "answer": "Manuscriptology is the study of manuscripts, focusing on the preservation and critical reading of handwritten historical documents."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 95,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the significance of 1737 C.E. for historians?",
      "answer": "It marks the year Gottingen University was founded in Germany, establishing the first independent department for history studies."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 96,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is 'Dialectics'?",
      "answer": "Dialectics is Hegel's method of analysis based on opposites used to understand the true nature of historical events."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 97,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Which book entitled 'The Histories' was written by Herodotus?",
      "answer": "Herodotus wrote 'The Histories' in the fifth century B.C.E., making it the first known book to use the term 'History'."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 98,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Who started the Annales School?",
      "answer": "The Annales School was started by French historians in the twentieth century to provide a new direction to history writing."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 99,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did Leopold von Ranké believe was reachable through his method?",
      "answer": "He believed that with his critical method of examining original documents, it was possible to reach the historical truth."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 100,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "In what terms does the human mind understand events according to Hegel?",
      "answer": "According to Hegel, the human mind understands the true nature of an event only in terms of two direct opposites like Good-Bad."
    },
  
    {
      "question_id": 101,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the meaning of the Greek term 'History' as used by Herodotus?",
      "answer": "Herodotus used the term to title his book 'The Histories', signifying an inquiry or a critical narrative of past events."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 102,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Why is historical research considered a continuous process?",
      "answer": "It is continuous because researchers constantly strive to understand the chronology and interconnections of past events through new evidence."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 103,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How do physical sciences verify knowledge?",
      "answer": "Physical sciences use the empirical method, involving laboratory experiments and observation, to prove laws irrespective of time and space."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 104,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the role of a conceptual framework in history writing?",
      "answer": "It determines the inclusion and interpretation of historical events and defines the historian's specific style of writing."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 105,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Name three disciplines useful in historical research mentioned in the text.",
      "answer": "Archaeology, Archival Science, and Manuscriptology are among the many disciplines useful for historical research."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 106,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the focus of modern historiography roots in ancient Greece?",
      "answer": "It focuses on the Greek tradition of recording history, where Herodotus first used the term 'History' for his scholarly work."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 107,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Describe the Sumerian tradition of recording battles.",
      "answer": "Sumerians preserved the names of kings and battle stories in inscriptions, dating as far back as 4500 B.C.E.."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 108,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was the eighteenth-century progress in European historiography?",
      "answer": "Scholars achieved progress in Philosophy and Science, believing social truths could be studied by applying scientific methods."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 109,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Who founded the first independent department of history?",
      "answer": "The Gottingen University in Germany, founded in 1737 C.E., established the first independent department of history."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 110,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the significance of René Descartes' book 'Discourse on the method'?",
      "answer": "It introduced rules that impacted scientific research, specifically insisting that nothing should be accepted as true if there is doubt."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 111,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How did Voltaire define the importance of social aspects in history?",
      "answer": "He argued that trade, economy, and agriculture were as important as objective truth and chronology for historiography."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 112,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was Hegel's view on the presentation of history?",
      "answer": "He insisted that historical reality should be presented logically and that presentation changes as new evidence emerges."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 113,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Define 'Dialectics' in one sentence.",
      "answer": "Dialectics is a method of analysis based on understanding opposites like True-False and Good-Bad to grasp an event's nature."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 114,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What are the components of the synthesis process in dialectics?",
      "answer": "It involves a 'Thesis' (initial theory), an 'Antithesis' (contrary theory), and a 'Synthesis' (new thesis combining both)."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 115,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was the influence of Leopold von Ranké on 19th-century historiography?",
      "answer": "He introduced critical research methods, emphasizing original documents and criticizing imaginative narration to reach historical truth."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 116,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How did Karl Marx view the nature of human history?",
      "answer": "Marx viewed human history as a history of class struggle, where the class owning production means exploits others."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 117,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did the Annales School recognize about history writing?",
      "answer": "It recognized that history includes climate, trade, and collective psychology, not just political events and leaders."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 118,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did Simone de Beauvoir contribute to feminism?",
      "answer": "Her writings helped establish the fundamentals of feminism, leading to the restructuring of history from a female perspective."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 119,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was the focus of feminist historiography after 1990?",
      "answer": "It focused on women as an independent social class, researching their employment, trade unions, and family life."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 120,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Explain Foucault's 'Archaeology of Knowledge'.",
      "answer": "It is a method that rejects strict chronology, focusing instead on explaining transitions in the past."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 121,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Which unacknowledged areas did Foucault subject to historical analysis?",
      "answer": "He analyzed psychological disorders, science of medicine, and prison administration."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 122,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How has the scope of historiography expanded over time?",
      "answer": "It now includes histories of literature, architecture, music, dance, drama, films, and television."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 123,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the purpose of formulating hypotheses in historical research?",
      "answer": "Hypotheses are formulated to provide a tentative explanation that guides the critical examination of various sources."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 124,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Why is comparative analysis important in collecting historical information?",
      "answer": "It helps highlight the processes leading to historical transitions by looking at similarities and differences across events."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 125,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What are the criteria for examining the authenticity of a document?",
      "answer": "Experts use lettering style, author's style, manufacturing date, type of paper, and stamps of authority."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 126,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How did ancient communities use cave paintings for history?",
      "answer": "Cave paintings were used to record and pass on stories of ancestor's life and valour to the next generation."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 127,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the significance of the 4500 B.C.E. Sumerian inscription?",
      "answer": "It is the earliest inscription recording a battle between two kingdoms, now displayed at the Louvre."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 128,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Why does history not suggest interrelation between Divine and human deeds?",
      "answer": "Because modern historiography is anthropocentric, focusing solely on the deeds of ancient human societies."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 129,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Mention any two German universities that became centers for historical studies.",
      "answer": "Gottingen University and Berlin University (associated with Ranke) were key centers in Germany."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 130,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was René Descartes' view on truth?",
      "answer": "He believed one should never accept anything as true until all grounds of doubt are excluded."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 131,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Who is known as the founder of modern historiography?",
      "answer": "Voltaire (François-Marie Arouet) is considered the founder of modern historiography."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 132,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did Hegel mean by 'historical reality should be presented logically'?",
      "answer": "He meant that the timeline of events should indicate human progress and be organized in a rational manner."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 133,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Which book by Hegel is well known for discussing history?",
      "answer": "'Reason in History' is the well-known book where Hegel presents his philosophical views on history."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 134,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Why did Ranké criticize imaginative narration?",
      "answer": "He believed history should be based strictly on facts found in original documents to reach the truth."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 135,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is 'Das Kapital'?",
      "answer": "It is a treatise written by Karl Marx that is the most referred book worldwide regarding his economic and social theories."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 136,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What was the new direction given by the Annales School?",
      "answer": "It moved history away from just politics and kings to include local people, climate, and collective psychology."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 137,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "How did feminist historiography change the male-dominated perspective?",
      "answer": "It emphasized rethinking history from women's perspective and including their roles in family and employment."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 138,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the 'Louvre' museum famous for in this chapter?",
      "answer": "It displays the earliest known fragment of an inscription from the Sumer civilization."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 139,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Who was François-Marie Arouet?",
      "answer": "He was the French scholar better known by his name 'Voltaire'."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 140,
      "SHORT": "SHORT",
      "question": "How does history present a 'graph of mankind's journey'?",
      "answer": "By documenting and analyzing past human deeds and their outcomes over time."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 141,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the importance of original documents to Ranké?",
      "answer": "They are the primary source for gathering information to reach the historical truth with greatest care."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 142,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What does 'Synthesis' represent in the dialectic process?",
      "answer": "It represents a new thesis that reconciles and includes the gist of both the thesis and antithesis."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 143,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What role does trade play in the Annales School's historiography?",
      "answer": "Trade is studied as part of the broader historical context alongside climate and technology."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 144,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Why is arranging events chronologically considered 'not right' by Foucault?",
      "answer": "He felt that archaeology should instead focus on explaining the transitions that occurred in the past."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 145,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did Foucault mean by the 'science of medicine' in historical analysis?",
      "answer": "He meant subjecting medical history and transitions to critical analysis to understand past changes."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 146,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is 'Numismatics'?",
      "answer": "It is the scientific study of coins, which serves as a discipline for historical research."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 147,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the significance of 'The Histories'?",
      "answer": "It is the title of the book by Herodotus, marking the first known use of the term 'History'."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 148,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What did European universities focus on before the 18th century?",
      "answer": "They focused primarily on philosophical discourses revolving around Divine phenomena."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 149,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "Name the scholars who contributed to the development of historiography.",
      "answer": "Notable scholars include René Descartes, Voltaire, Hegel, Ranke, Karl Marx, and Foucault."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 150,
      "question_type": "SHORT",
      "question": "What is the objective of historical studies according to the text?",
      "answer": "The objective is understanding the chronology of past events and their interconnections."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 151,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain the characteristics of Modern Historiography as described in the chapter.",
      "answer": "Modern historiography is defined by four main characteristics. First, its method is based on scientific principles, starting with the formation of relevant questions. Second, these questions are anthropocentric, focusing on the deeds of ancient human societies rather than divine intervention. Third, the answers to these questions are supported by reliable historical evidence. Finally, history presents a graph of mankind's journey by analyzing these past human deeds. These characteristics distinguish modern history from ancient storytelling."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 152,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Describe the 'Dialectics' method of analysis as proposed by Hegel.",
      "answer": "Hegel proposed 'Dialectics' to understand the true nature of historical events through opposites. The human mind cannot understand an event without opposites like True-False or Good-Bad. The process begins with a 'Thesis', a theory proposed at the start. This is followed by an 'Antithesis', a contrary theory. After a thorough logical discussion, a 'Synthesis' is proposed. The synthesis includes the gist of both the thesis and the antithesis. This arriving at a new thesis is a continuous process of historical understanding."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 153,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What is Karl Marx's 'Class Theory' and its significance in history?",
      "answer": "Karl Marx argued that history is not about abstract ideas but about living people and their relationships. These relationships are shaped by fundamental needs and the ownership of the means of production. Since accessibility to these means is unequal, society divides into classes, leading to class struggle. Marx stated that human history is the history of class struggle, where the ruling class exploits others. His views provided a new thesis for historiography in the late 19th century. His treatise 'Das Kapital' is a central reference for this theory globally."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 154,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain the significance and impact of the Annales School on historiography.",
      "answer": "The Annales School was started by French historians at the beginning of the 20th century. It gave a new direction to history writing by moving beyond just political events and great leaders. The school emphasized studying the lives of local people and their environment. Key themes included climate, agriculture, trade, and technology. It also explored means of communication, social divisions, and collective psychology. This shift allowed for a more comprehensive understanding of historical times beyond diplomacy and wars."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 155,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the contribution of Michel Foucault to the field of historiography.",
      "answer": "Michel Foucault, a 20th-century French historian, introduced the concept of 'Archaeology of Knowledge'. In his book, he argued against the traditional practice of arranging events in a strict chronological order. Foucault felt that archaeology's goal is not to find ultimate historical truth but to explain transitions in the past. He called his method 'the archaeology of knowledge' because it looks deeper into historical changes. He also analyzed unacknowledged areas like psychological disorders and prison administration. His work expanded the scope of historiography to include varied social and scientific subjects."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 156,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What is Feminist Historiography, and how did it change historical research?",
      "answer": "Feminist historiography involves restructuring history from the perspective of women. It was pioneered by writers like Simone de Beauvoir, who established the fundamentals of feminism. This approach shifted research to focus on women’s employment, roles in trade unions, and family life. It also moved history away from a purely male-dominated perspective. After 1990, women were portrayed in historical writings as an independent social class. This research drove a focus on the institutions working for women's causes throughout history."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 157,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain Leopold von Ranke's perspective on historical research.",
      "answer": "Leopold von Ranke of Berlin University greatly influenced 19th-century historiography with his critical method. He insisted that historical truth could only be reached by examining original documents with the greatest care. Ranke believed all documents associated with an event must be thoroughly scrutinized. He was a strong critic of imaginative narration in history. His articles are collected in 'The Theory and Practice of History' and 'The Secret of World History'. His focus was on the utmost reliability of evidence in historical studies."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 158,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the scientific perspective in Europe influence the development of historiography?",
      "answer": "By the 18th century, Europe made significant progress in Philosophy and Science. Scholars began to believe that social and historical truths could be studied using scientific methods. This led to a shift toward objectivity in history and historiography. Philosophical discussions moved away from Divine phenomena toward empirical truths. The founding of Gottingen University in 1737 was a major milestone, as it had an independent history department. Subsequently, other German universities became centers for critical historical studies based on these perspectives."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 159,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Describe the methods and challenges involved in historical research.",
      "answer": "Historical research involves examining sources, formulating hypotheses, and writing narratives. A major challenge is that researchers cannot use laboratory experiments or direct observation as events cannot be recreated. To begin, an expert in ancient languages and scripts is needed to read and understand documents. Experts must also verify authenticity using criteria like lettering style and manufacturing date. The researcher must then scrutinize the document with relevant historical references. Finally, information is collected to highlight processes leading to transitions."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 160,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What was Voltaire's contribution to modern historiography?",
      "answer": "Voltaire, originally named François-Marie Arouet, is considered the founder of modern historiography. He argued that history is more than just objective truth and chronology. He insisted that understanding all aspects of human life is crucial for history writing. This includes considering social traditions, trade, economy, and agriculture as equally important factors. His views gave rise to the thought that historical narratives should be holistic. By including these diverse human elements, he reshaped the way history is recorded."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 161,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Examine the tradition of historiography from ancient to modern times.",
      "answer": "Ancient societies did not write critical narratives but used cave paintings, story-telling, and ballads to preserve history. The tradition of recording events can be traced back to the Sumer civilization in Mesopotamia. Sumerian kings' names and battle stories were preserved in inscriptions, like those in the Louvre museum. Modern historiography began to take shape with the Greek historian Herodotus in the 5th century B.C.E.. In the 18th century, it evolved into a scientific discipline focused on objectivity. Today, it is a continuous process of critically examining various sources to understand the past."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 162,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain the concept of 'Archaeology of Knowledge' and its focus on transitions.",
      "answer": "Michel Foucault introduced 'Archaeology of Knowledge' to challenge the practice of chronological history. He argued that archaeology does not seek ultimate historical truth. Instead, it attempts to explain various transitions that have occurred in the past. Foucault believed that explaining these shifts or transitions in history is the more important goal. He used this method to analyze areas like psychological disorders and prison administration. This perspective suggests that history is a series of changes rather than a linear journey."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 163,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What are the various disciplines that assist in historical research?",
      "answer": "Several specialized disciplines are useful for conducting thorough historical research. Archaeology provides physical evidence through excavation, while Archival Science manages historical records. Manuscriptology involves the study of old manuscripts, and Epigraphy is the study of inscriptions. Analysis of lettering style and Linguistics help in understanding scripts and languages. Numismatics involves the study of coins, which provides economic and chronological data. Genealogy, the study of lineage, is also essential for tracking family and historical connections."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 164,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the significance of the earliest inscription in the Louvre museum.",
      "answer": "The Louvre museum houses a fragment of the earliest known historical inscription. It dates back to 4500 B.C.E. and records a battle between two kingdoms in the Sumer civilization. The inscription depicts a forward-marching file of soldiers holding shields and spears, led by a General. This shows that the tradition of recording historical events is ancient. Names of Sumerian kings and their stories of battles were preserved this way. It serves as a primary source for understanding the origins of recorded history."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 165,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the focus of history writing change after the nineteenth century?",
      "answer": "Before the 19th century, history often focused on kings and political events. In the late 19th century, Karl Marx introduced class struggle as a central theme. In the 20th century, the Annales School expanded this further to include climate, trade, and local people. Feminist historiography then restructured narratives from women’s perspective. Michel Foucault later shifted the focus to explaining transitions in knowledge and social areas like medicine. The scope now encompasses literature, architecture, and even films and television."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 166,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain the role of René Descartes in promoting the critical examination of documents.",
      "answer": "René Descartes was a foremost scholar who insisted on the reliability of historical documents. In his book 'Discourse on the method', he gave rules for scientific research. His primary rule was never to accept anything for true till all grounds of doubt are excluded. He emphasized that historians must critically examine and verify documents before using them. This approach had a great impact on the scientific method used in historical research. It moved historiography toward a more skeptical and accurate study of the past."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 167,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What is the process of synthesizing a new thesis in Hegel's dialectics?",
      "answer": "Synthesizing a new thesis involves a logical progression through direct opposites. First, a theory called 'Thesis' is proposed. Next, a contrary theory called 'Antithesis' is presented. A thorough logical discussion of both occurs to find the truth. This process results in a 'Synthesis', which includes the gist of both theories. Arriving at this synthesis is how the human mind grasps the true nature of historical reality. This synthesized result eventually becomes a new thesis for further exploration."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 168,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Why is historical narrative never fully complete and always a 'continuous process'?",
      "answer": "History is a continuous process because the understanding of the past evolves with new evidence. A historian cannot include every single past event in their narrative. Selection depends on the conceptual framework and the questions the historian asks. As philosophies change, like the move toward objectivity in the 18th century, narratives are rewritten. New schools of thought, like the Annales or Feminist schools, also lead to restructuring old stories. Thus, historical research is always open to re-examination and new interconnections."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 169,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the importance of anthropocentrism in modern historiography.",
      "answer": "Anthropocentrism is a defining characteristic that separates modern history from ancient myths. It means that historical questions are focused specifically on the deeds of humans in ancient societies. History does not suggest any interrelation between the Divine and human deeds. This allows historiography to be based on scientific principles rather than religious beliefs. By focusing on human journey and deeds, historians can provide supported answers with reliable evidence. This perspective makes history a social science concerned with human progress."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 170,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did ancient people preserve historical memories before writing was prevalent?",
      "answer": "Ancient people felt a strong need to pass on stories of the life and valour of their ancestors. Communities all over the world used various creative means for this purpose. Cave paintings were used as visual records of their experiences. Story-telling was a key oral tradition for keeping history alive across generations. They also used singing songs and ballads to celebrate ancestral deeds. In modern historiography, these traditional means are now looked upon as valuable sources of history."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 171,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain the significance of Herodotus in the development of Western historiography.",
      "answer": "Herodotus, a 5th-century B.C.E. Greek historian, is a foundational figure in Western historiography. He was the first to use the term 'History' for his scholarly book. His work, entitled 'The Histories', established a tradition of recording past events in a written format. This Greek approach influenced the scientific characteristics of modern historiography. By documenting human events, he moved away from purely mythological storytelling. His contribution marks the shift from oral tradition to a more structured historical narrative in the West."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 172,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What role does reliable evidence play in modern history writing?",
      "answer": "Reliable evidence is the pillar that supports the answers to historical questions. Modern historiography requires that any claim about the past must be backed by verifiable sources. This evidence comes from sources like inscriptions, coins, and original documents examined by experts. Using evidence allows history to present an accurate graph of mankind's journey. Without reliable evidence, historical narratives would be considered imaginative rather than scholarly. It ensures that historical truths are consistent with the available records of human deeds."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 173,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the ownership of the means of production shape history according to Marx?",
      "answer": "Karl Marx believed that the ownership of means of production is the primary driver of human relationships. Since this ownership is usually concentrated in one class, it creates social inequality. This inequality leads to the division of society into classes, which results in class struggle. The class that owns the means of production economically exploits the rest of the society. Therefore, human history is fundamentally the history of these class struggles and economic exploitation. His theory shifted the focus of history from abstract ideas to the material conditions of living people."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 174,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the criteria used by experts to examine the authenticity of a document.",
      "answer": "Experts use several rigorous criteria to ensure a historical document is authentic. They analyze the lettering style and the author's unique style of writing. They also check the manufacturing date and the type of paper used for that specific period. Stamps of authority are examined to verify the document's origin. The document is further scrutinized using relevant historical references to check for consistency. Finally, the expert must understand the language and script to read and interpret its meaning correctly."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 175,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What themes were included in the Annales school beyond politics and leadership?",
      "answer": "The Annales School expanded the scope of history to include a wide array of social and environmental themes. It moved beyond political events and kings to study climate and its impact on history. Local people and their way of life became central subjects. Agriculture, trade, and technology were studied to understand economic transitions. The school also looked at means of communication and social divisions. Most notably, it included collective psychology, examining how groups of people thought during different historical times."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 176,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Describe the evolution of historical research methods as presented in the chapter.",
      "answer": "Historical research begins with formulating relevant questions based on historical references. It involves collecting information and highlighting processes leading to transitions. Researchers must examine references and critically examine sources to formulate hypotheses. The method includes comparative analysis of information. Disciplines like archaeology and numismatics are used to gather diverse data. Finally, a historian writes a critical historical narrative after scrutinizing all relevant documents. This method ensures that the narrative is a critical and evidence-based account."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 177,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did Simone de Beauvoir establish the fundamentals of feminism in history?",
      "answer": "Simone de Beauvoir, a French writer, helped establish feminism by restructuring history from a female perspective. Her writings emphasized rethinking the male-dominated perspective that had ignored women's roles. She argued for the inclusion of women in historical narratives as active participants. This led research to focus on women's employment, trade union roles, and family life. Her work paved the way for women to be portrayed as an independent social class in historical writings. It significantly shifted the focus of 20th-century historiography toward gender equality."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 178,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the role of German universities in the development of scientific historiography.",
      "answer": "German universities were instrumental in making history an independent academic discipline. Gottingen University, founded in 1737, was the first to have a history department. This led other German universities to become centers for critical historical studies. Scholars like Hegel and Leopold von Ranke, who taught at Berlin University, brought scientific rigor to the field. Ranke’s emphasis on original documents and critical research set new standards for historiography. Their work transitioned history from philosophical discourse to an evidence-based social science."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 179,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What is 'Epigraphy' and how does it contribute to historical knowledge?",
      "answer": "Epigraphy is the specialized study of inscriptions found on ancient artifacts and monuments. It provides primary evidence of historical names, dates, and events. Inscriptions like the Sumerian records in the Louvre museum offer direct insight into ancient warfare and leadership. Epigraphy helps in understanding the chronology of kings and kingdoms. It is a critical discipline for verifying information when written books are not available. By deciphering these inscriptions, historians can reconstruct the stories of ancient human societies accurately."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 180,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain how modern historiography is built on scientific principles.",
      "answer": "Modern historiography is scientific because its method begins with forming relevant, testable questions. These questions are anthropocentric and supported by reliable historical evidence. The process involves critically examining various sources and formulating hypotheses. Historians use comparative analysis to understand transitions in the past. Disciplines like archaeology, numismatics, and linguistics are used to verify data. This evidence-based approach ensures that history presents a logical and accurate graph of mankind's journey."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 181,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the importance of 'Reason in History' in Hegel's philosophy.",
      "answer": "In his book 'Reason in History', Hegel argued that historical reality should be presented in a logical and rational manner. He believed that the timeline of events indicates human progress over time. To Hegel, historical methods were not of lesser quality than scientific ones. He insisted that history is bound to change as new evidence comes forth. This philosophical view made history an academic discipline focused on the logical progression of human reason. His philosophy influenced many scholars to see history as a logical timeline."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 182,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the scope of historiography expand to include arts and television?",
      "answer": "As historiography evolved, its scope continuously expanded to encompass various facets of human culture. Writing histories moved beyond politics to include subjects like literature and architecture. Sculpture, drawing, and painting were also subjected to historical analysis. Performing arts like music, dance, and drama became part of historical records. Most recently, modern media like films and television have been included in historiography. This expansion reflects the modern belief that all aspects of human life have a historical narrative worth exploring."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 183,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Describe the significance of the Sumerian civilization in the history of recording battles.",
      "answer": "The Sumer civilization in Mesopotamia is where the tradition of recording historical events began. Names of Sumerian kings and the stories of battles fought by them were preserved in various inscriptions. These records, such as the fragment from 4500 B.C.E., provide the earliest evidence of military history. The inscriptions show organized soldiers and generals, indicating a complex society. This tradition eventually spread to other civilizations, forming the roots of historiography. Today, these records are crucial for understanding the political transitions of ancient times."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 184,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What is the 'Empirical method' and why is it distinguished from historical methods?",
      "answer": "The empirical method is a laboratory method of experiments and observation used to verify knowledge in physical sciences. It allows formulating laws that remain true regardless of time and space and can be proved repeatedly. In historical research, this method cannot be used because historical events cannot be recreated. We were not present in historical time and space to observe them directly. Also, history cannot formulate universal laws that remain true across all space and time. Instead, history relies on critical examination of evidence."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 185,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the conceptual framework adopted by a historian determine their writing style?",
      "answer": "The conceptual framework acts as a lens through which a historian views the past. It dictates which events are included in the narrative and which are left out. The framework also determines how these events are interpreted and what meaning is assigned to them. Consequently, the historian’s style of writing and the overall tone of the narrative are defined by this framework. For example, a Marxist framework focuses on class struggle, while a feminist framework focuses on women's lives. This framework makes historical narrative a critical interpretation rather than just a list of facts."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 186,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the influence of the eighteenth-century Enlightenment on history writing.",
      "answer": "The Enlightenment led to progress in Philosophy and Science, which changed history writing. Scholars began to prioritize objectivity and scientific principles in historiography. Philosophical discussions shifted away from Divine phenomena toward social and historical truths. This period saw the founding of Gottingen University, which established history as an independent department. Scholars were encouraged to apply scientific methods to study the human past. This intellectual shift laid the foundation for modern historiography to be a rational and critical social science."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 187,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain the importance of 'Genealogy' and 'Linguistics' in historical research.",
      "answer": "Genealogy and Linguistics are key disciplines that assist historians in verifying and interpreting information. Genealogy is the study of lineage, which helps track family connections and royal successions throughout history. Linguistics is the study of language and its evolution, which is crucial for reading ancient scripts and understanding historical context. Together, they help in analyzing the authenticity and origin of historical documents. These disciplines provide a multi-dimensional view of the past by looking at human relationships and communication. They ensure that the historical narrative is based on accurate biological and cultural data."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 188,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What did Michel Foucault mean by explaining transitions in history being 'more important'?",
      "answer": "Foucault felt that a simple chronological list of events does not provide a true understanding of history. Instead, he focused on explaining 'transitions'—the shifts in how society thinks and functions. These transitions reveal deeper changes in knowledge, such as the science of medicine or prison administration. By explaining why these transitions occurred, Foucault provided a more analytical view of the past. He called his method 'the archaeology of knowledge' because it digs beneath the surface of traditional timelines. This approach helps understand the underlying processes that cause historical change."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 189,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Describe the content and style of the earliest inscription fragment known.",
      "answer": "The fragment of the earliest inscription shows a forward-marching file of soldiers holding shields and spears. A General is seen leading the soldiers from the front. It is written in the tradition of the Sumer civilization from Mesopotamia. The inscription records a battle fought between two ancient kingdoms. It is a visual and written record of military history dating to 4500 B.C.E.. This artifact demonstrates the early human need to record valour and battles for posterity. It is now displayed in the Louvre museum as a primary historical source."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 190,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the Annales school move history toward 'Collective Psychology'?",
      "answer": "The Annales School believed that understanding history requires knowing how large groups of people thought. Beyond just studying kings and politics, it focused on the common mentalities of local people. Collective psychology involves studying the shared beliefs, fears, and attitudes of a society in a particular period. This allowed historians to explain why certain social transitions occurred based on public mindset. Along with climate and trade, collective psychology provided a more social and psychological dimension to historiography. It made history a more holistic study of human civilization."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 191,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the importance of original documents to Leopold von Ranke.",
      "answer": "Leopold von Ranke believed that information gathered through original documents was of the utmost importance. He argued that only these original sources could lead to historical truth. Ranke insisted that all documents associated with an event must be examined with the greatest care. This approach minimized the bias and imagination of the historian. By relying strictly on primary evidence, Ranke brought a higher level of objectivity to historiography. His methods influenced the nineteenth century to become an era of critical and documented history writing."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 192,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the 1990s change the portrayal of women in historical writing?",
      "answer": "In historical writings after 1990, women were portrayed as an independent social class. This was a shift from previous decades where their roles were often secondary to men. Historical research began to focus in depth on various aspects of women's lives. This included their specific roles in employment and their participation in trade unions. Institutions working for women's causes and their family life were also thoroughly researched. This portrayal recognized women’s agency and their distinct contributions to historical transitions."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 193,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Explain the role of 'Hypotheses' in the historical research process.",
      "answer": "Formulating hypotheses is a mandatory step in the historical research method. A hypothesis provides a tentative explanation or framework for a historical event. It guides the historian in choosing which sources to examine and which questions to ask. Hypotheses are then tested and proven against the available reliable evidence. If the evidence contradicts the hypothesis, it is reformulated. This ensures that the final historical narrative is a logical result of critical examination rather than random facts."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 194,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What is 'Archival Science' and how does it support the historian?",
      "answer": "Archival Science is a discipline focused on the organization, preservation, and management of historical documents. It supports historians by ensuring that original documents are safe and accessible for research. Archives serve as repositories for letters, government records, and maps used as primary evidence. Archival science also involves cataloging documents so historians can find relevant references quickly. By maintaining the integrity of sources, it allows for the critical examination that René Descartes and Ranke advocated. It is essential for the continuous process of historiography."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 195,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the roots of modern historiography in ancient Greek traditions.",
      "answer": "Modern historiography with its scientific characteristics traces its roots back to ancient Greece. The Greek term 'History' was used first by Herodotus for his scholarly book 'The Histories'. This marked the transition toward recording human deeds as a critical narrative. Greek historians prioritized documenting the deeds of members of human societies. This human-centric approach is the basis for the anthropocentric questions in modern historiography. The Greek tradition of inquiring into the past provided the conceptual foundation for the logical presentation of history."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 196,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the access to means of production lead to class exploitation according to Marx?",
      "answer": "Marx argued that the class that owns the means of production economically exploits the rest of society. Since the means of production are necessary to meet fundamental human needs, those who own them hold significant power. Accessibility to these means is not equal among different strata of society. This inequality forces those without means to work for those who do, creating an exploitative relationship. This dynamic results in class struggle, which Marx identified as the driving force of history. His theory emphasized that historical transitions are caused by these economic tensions."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 197,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Describe the continuous process of re-examining interconnections in history.",
      "answer": "Historical research is a continuous process aimed at understanding the chronology of events and their interconnections. As new evidence is discovered, historians must re-examine existing narratives. This leads to highlighting new processes that lead to historical transitions. Comparative analysis allows for deeper understanding of how different events are linked. Historians also adopt new conceptual frameworks, which change how interconnections are interpreted. This ensures that history is a dynamic field that reflects modern scholarly progress and evidence."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 198,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "What did René Descartes mean by excluding 'all grounds of doubt'?",
      "answer": "Descartes insisted that a historian should never accept anything as true if it can be doubted. This means every historical document must be critically examined for reliability and authenticity. Experts must use criteria like writing style and manufacturing dates to remove any suspicion of forgery. Only after a source has passed every critical test can it be used as the basis for truth. This rule promotes a rigorous scientific method of research in historiography. It prevents imaginative narration and ensures history is built on solid facts."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 199,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "Discuss the significance of 'The Theory and Practice of History' and its focus on truth.",
      "answer": "This book is a collection of articles by Leopold von Ranke that emphasizes his critical method. It advocates for the use of original documents to reach the historical truth. The focus is on examining associated documents with greatest care to avoid imaginative stories. It represents the nineteenth-century shift toward critical historical research. Ranke believed that truth is accessible if the researcher remains objective and relies on facts. His work in this book set a new academic standard for documenting history globally."
    },
    {
      "question_id": 200,
      "question_type": "LONG",
      "question": "How did the 18th century German universities pave the way for modern history departments?",
      "answer": "In 1737 C.E., Gottingen University was founded in Germany with the first independent department of history. This was a major departure from universities that only studied Divine phenomena. It established history as a separate field from philosophy. Following this, other German universities also became centers for historical studies. This led to a boom in historical research based on scientific principles. The academic environment in Germany fostered notable scholars like Hegel and Ranke, who modernized the discipline. Thus, these universities were the birthplaces of modern professional historiography."
    }
  ]
}